Dominique "Nikki" Esguerra

Modesto, CA • (209) 614-0294 • ddesguerra@ucdavis.edu linkedin.com/in/nikkiesg • github.com/desguerra • desguerra.github.io

SUMMARY

Full-stack Web Developer with a Bachelor of Science degree in Electrical Engineering. Currently pursuing a certificate in Full-Stack Web Development at the University of California, Davis. Effective at combining problem-solving, adaptability, and communication in fast-paced environments to build joyful and meaningful experiences for users.

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate

University of California, Davis

June 2022 - December 2022

★ 24-week intensive program focused on gaining full-stack technical programming skills in JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, ReactJS, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Handelbars.js

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

University of California, Davis

Graduated June 2020

★ Awards: Dean's List, UC Davis College of Engineering Winter 2017

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, SQL, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Bootstrap, Python, Java **Applications/Tools**: Node.js, React, Express.js, MongoDB, Handelbars.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Jest

PROJECTS

Projects Portfolio Website | github.com/desguerra/desguerra.github.io | desguerra.github.io

★ Online professional portfolio utilizing JavaScript, HTML, and CSS on GitHub

Tech Blog | github.com/desguerra/tech-blog | afternoon-chamber-17636.herokuapp.com

- ★ Full-stack web application that follows the Model-View-Controller architectural structure where developers can publish blog posts and comment on other developers' posts
- ★ Made from scratch utilizing Handlebar.js as the template engine, Sequelize as the ORM, the express-session npm package for authentication, and is deployed on Heroku

EXPERIENCE

Computer Science Instructor & Instructor Success Specialist | JUNI LEARNING - Remote, CA November 2020 - May 2022

- ★ Executed 1:1 Computer Science lesson plans through JavaScript, Scratch, Python, Java, and C++ courses for students ages 8-18, while adapting to student needs and interests
- ★ Communicated with parents on a regular basis, providing updates on student progress and results from homework and learning assessments
- ★ Maintained records for each student, covering multiple courses and skill levels
- ★ Led and evaluated part-time instructor performance every other week, administering raises, promotions, or personal re-trainings when applicable

Lead Web Developer | SACHACKS - Sacramento, CA

March 2019-June 2020

- ★ Managed SacHacks' web development team and served as a single point of contact to coordinate between our team and executives of the organization
- ★ Developed user-friendly homesite for SacHacks using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- ★ Managed and maintained live website during the weekend-long hack-a-thon event